you know I as I'm talking about this I
just started scrolling through there and
I see a vulnerability that's hilarious
uh well going to go ahead and uh
bookmark that
[Music]
that
hey guys ever since word fence did their
campaign back in December I've been deep
diving everything I can get my hands on
with regards to Wordpress security and
naturally I wanted to talk to you guys
about that on the Pod and so I grabbed
word fence security researcher Ram Gul
brought him on the Pod to discuss some
of the nitty-gritty details of hacking
WordPress plugins um it's a pretty
technical episode we get pretty in depth
on what kind of functions are called uh
to register routes within WordPress what
kind of common vulnerabilities you see
um and patterns that RAM and the word
fence team have identified over the
years which lead to Wordpress
vulnerabilities um so a lot of great
content I really think you'll enjoy it
in conjunction with that word fence is
relaunching their campaign that they had
in December and offering 6.25 times the
normal Bounty amounts and they've told
me that they're going to keep on
offering amazing opportunities like this
to researchers so you'll definitely want
to head over to ctbb showw and sign up
for a researcher account on the word
fence platform so you can stay in the
loop with that and it's a great way to
support the show so I think that's it
with that let's go ahead and get into
the episode all righty we're rolling Ram
welcome to the Pod man hi I'm happy to
be here dude yeah this this episode's
gonna be great and I have to say I'm I'm
uh I'm excited for it even though I just
got pulled out of the hot tub to record
this episode when it's snowing outside
man oh man that's the best I know like I
just I don't you know if there was a
time time to be in the hot tub it's when
it snows but ABS um there's a lot of
great content in this episode looking
through this Dock and it is chalk full
of awesome awesome information about
WordPress um so just to give the uh the
listeners a little bit of background uh
RAM you work for word fence and uh RAM
does some very impressive uh security
research on WordPress and so our thought
today was let's go ahead and dive into
some of these more nuanced WordPress
based uh knowledge that you need to hack
WordPress plugins because ever since we
did the sponsorship in December I've
just been like deep diving that [__] and
I love it um so now I get now my chance
comes to geek out over this and Ram's
the perfect guy um to do it with so with
that Ram um I was hoping we can start
with your bugs in particular um so uh
just like every other guest we're gonna
put Ram through the uh through the give
us a cool bug um ringer here and let's
start with the uh subscriber Plus rce on
uh Elemental if you want to kind of just
give us the rundown of that one sure uh
so uh this is only around for a couple
versions uh but Elementor introduced a
new functionality for their onboarding
module and uh they had an action running
on admin in it which basically runs
anytime you're on any admin page
regardless of whether or not you're an
administrator right um it wasn't using a
normal Ajax listener it actually had
their own like custom Ajax listener just
like are we doing Ajax yes okay cool
then take care of this um and all it
used was a not
check and uh effectively what it would
allow you to do
was it was intended to allow you to
upload and install the pro version of
Elementor uh but you could just feed it
any old zip file and stick your you know
webshell in there and uh if you were a
subscriber you grabb the knots off the
admin page uh upload the pro upgrade zip
and Bam you on the box wow dude okay so
let me get this straight Elementor is
also the it's like a five million
install plug it's like the biggest that
but WordPress doesn't they stop counting
after five oh do they really oh my gosh
that's crazy and I think if you look on
their website it says 10 million
Elementor does but so this this was when
they were um they implemented this
functionality when they were uh
including some pro upgrade stuff and so
the whole functionality on this is to
actually put PHP files on the web server
right yeah yeah so I mean it was working
as intended just not from an access
control perspective exactly and and this
actually goes to a topic that I can't
wait to talk about later with you which
is essentially non non acquisition as
access controls which is something that
we see quite a bit um in WordPress I
think and and so actually this this
brings to my mind that there's a bunch
of other nuanced things about WordPress
for example ad action and admin andit
that we haven't really covered for the
listeners just yet um and so what I
think we'll do is we may even swing back
around to this vulnerability even though
this one's pretty simple to understand
it's just a it's a um you know a
arbitrary you know PHP file upload on
the most you know popular WordPress
plug-in out there um and we'll we'll
come back to this once we've covered a
little bit more of the basics of
Wordpress um functionality and then
we'll go to the rest of your bugs too um
so with that what I had in mind for this
beginning part is like we're talking to
you know with our audience here Ram
we're talking to a lot of people that
know stuff about
web pen testing right but may not know
the intricacies of Wordpress and all the
weird [__] that WordPress does um and so
what I'm hoping to do is kind of T have
you talk us through some of the crazy
stuff I've been learning about with ADD
action and then all these different
hooks that we can we can hook functions
into um and then start to see what it
looks like to identify sources and syncs
in a in a WordPress application um so
let's let's go ahead and start from
there uh let's talk about add action and
how that Works in conjunction with um
these various hooks admin and nit uh
wpor Ajax uncore and that sort of thing
all right uh so realistically bread and
butter is uh WP Ajax there's a WP admin
admin Ajax endpoint and basically
everything uses it um for everything
including stuff that doesn't actually
need Ajax functionality right right it's
just the endp point if you want to get
stuff done uh it accepts an action
parameter um by default you have to be
authentic but that's all uh you can set
it to allow unauthenticated users and
plugins have mostly stop doing that
because that's you know generally not a
great idea yeah um but you know it it's
pretty basic you know it just accepts a
request or post you get parameter and uh
sometimes you know processes within the
actual call back sometimes it calls
another call back but gotcha so so
there's this there's this so unlike
other PHP applications where you
navigate to specific PHP files and
execute the PHP inside those files with
WordPress there's the opportunity for us
to um hook create hooks in the
application that correlate to different
paths on the WordPress core
functionality right and so add action is
is one of the ways to do that with um
and there's various types of of hooks in
there admin and nit uh being one of them
uh WPI Ajax underscore and then sum
string being another one and what those
allow us to do is interact with core
files right like like um uh what is it
wp-admin admin ajax.php is that right
yeah that's the end point that uh if you
if you send something to that endpoint
you add a you add a wpx hooks anywhere
in any active plugin and uh it'll call
whatever call back you have set right so
so instead of hitting direct PHP files
we can trigger functionality in these
WordPress apps by this admin uh you know
this inter pH which says has admin
written all over it admin in it uh admin
ajax.php
buttion admin action right but
unfortunately can also be hit by
unauthenticated users and triggered is
that correct that's correct yeah so
that's that's kind of nuts that was one
of the things when I first you know
after we we launched the campaign back
in December I was just really like wow I
can't believe this is how this works
like this is so easy to make a mistake
on I mean if you do it right it's not
that bad but you know a lot of people
don't do it right yeah yeah just the
naming convention is a little a little
bit tricky too you know with all the
admin and then and then you know and
we'll cover this probably a little bit
later but there's also a function called
isore admin right in the not what you
think it is right it's not checking
whether it's an admin it's checking
whether the request originated from an
administrative page right yeah yeah so
there anywhere in the admin panel even
if you're unauthenticated there's some
pages that are on in the admin folder
that will trigger that so it's crazy man
it's crazy so there's lots of lots of
sources so we've got admin and it um
that's the hook that that can trigger on
various accessing of various pages so
for example if you wanted to trigger an
admin in it hook you could visit pretty
much anything under
wp-admin right yeah yeah admin WP
adminadmin dpost is pretty common uh
that was originally designed similar to
xmlrpc to uh you know allow people to
just fire off new posts without logging
into the whole admin p I'll just
basically uh automate it wow that's
that's that's a lot man so so and then
you know by hitting those endpoints
admin post or admin Ajax we can trigger
that call back function so the add
action call which is something that that
we can this provided by WordPress takes
a hook so admin init or admin wpor aore
plus a callback function and then it
triggers that callback function so then
you know we can start executing forcing
that code to execute and a lot of times
that's making decisions off of of our
you know input right like post and get
like you know dollar signore poost
dollar signore getet and that sort of
thing and that's sort of like for those
people that are listening that know PHP
but haven't done WordPress stuff this is
the sort of hidden attack surface that
the WordPress plugins are hiding behind
where you can really pop some crazy
bones would you say that's accurate Ram
I would say that is extremely accurate
there WordPress relies on a lot of user
input and uh core is actually pretty
secure these days pretty secure but yeah
a lot of plugin developers you know it's
an open source ecosystem anyone can post
their code and uh right yeah a lot of
people learn by doing yeah I I I imagine
uh imagine there's lots of mistakes
being made which is one of the really
cool things about the word fence bug
Bounty program too is that constantly
there's new you know plugins being added
to the scope as things pass 50,000
installs um so the people that are you
know messing around and finding out so
to speak uh you know and then find
success and get over 50,000 installs all
of a sudden their code is up for review
which is something that's a really good
opportunity I think
absolutely so okay so now we know you
know how we can access some of this
attack surface right there there'll be
these calls to admin uh add action and
then there'll be these you know hooks
specified admin andit admin post um WP
aore and we'll Link in the description
of this episode a PDF file common
WordPress vulnerabilities and prevention
through secure coding best practices
it's kind of a mou
but it's a PDF file released by word
fence that documents all these
interesting Hooks and stuff like that so
we're able to trigger code from for
running and now we're looking to have
our user
input affect the server in some way
right because that's how the you know
vulnerabilities are made um we trigger
some code and then it takes our input
and something happens um so what are the
most common ways user input is accessed
in a WordPress
application um well are you talking
talking about syns or you talking about
I'm talking mostly about sources still
like like I guess you know the
traditional method would be in PHP you
know you've got the dollar signore get
or dollar signore poost super globals
yeah yeah I'm sure we have those in
WordPress too is there any other ones we
should be aware of or is it just those
PHP based ones um a lot of uh word press
plugins use uh get query VAR uh that's
usually for the specific WordPress
search
functionality um you know some people
use filter input uh which does not
actually uh sanitize your input unless
you tell it to exactly see that a lot uh
you'll also find some uh plugins using
customer Quest parsing functions that
just use the super globals or filter
input but you know call it something
fancy so uh it can if you you know
you're just using a Rex to search
through a whole bunch of files you might
miss something like that because they're
all using a you know specific function
to par requests sure yeah that's one of
the difficulties that I've kind of run
into with automating uh WordPress
vulnerability analysis cuz when I saw
this opportunity of like wow there's new
scope coming in you know there's new
plugins coming into scope every week you
know every day sometimes and uh you know
these are old and you know might be
untouched even sometimes um I was
thinking wow it'd be great if I could
just run some static analysis tools on
these on a regular basis and extract
information out but like it's not always
a simple tracing user input because when
it can come from you know it can be
abstracted behind all these functions
you know they can use input uncore get
you know get or input uncore post and
they can also use the dollar signore
sort of functionalities that come
attached with uh PHP so there's a
variety of things you kind of need to be
aware of when yeah there there's huge
variety of coding Styles and uh it it
does make it really hard to do static
analysis I mean there is there is a sort
of Wordpress recommended coding St
standard but uh you know not everyone
uses it they're getting people on board
but yeah now that that seems like
something really interesting and
something that should be uh globally
applied to maybe all of these plugins
and then maybe like a badge added or
something like that to the uh to the you
know wordpress.org plugins page or
something if they comply with it I think
that'd be really cool yeah that's not a
bad idea um so regarding these these uh
you know Ajax functions or this
functionality that we can trigger using
uh you know these core PHP hooks uh what
is so the these do not have any
functioning in place protection for SE
surf is that correct correct they don't
uh they don't have any in place Access
Control they don't have any in Place SE
surf ah and you know love to hear it I'm
sorry I just you know I know it
shouldn't make have working content
security policy on unless you add it and
you know fuss with everything to
actually make it compatible so oh my
gosh yeah no I mean I hate to love it
you know I love it but I hate it but I
love it you
know you know being on the offensive
side you got this sort of you know pull
of the heart in in each Direction
exactly exactly it's just so much fun um
but yeah and that does make these T
these functions particularly
um enticing for an attacker right
because there's no built-in default
Access Control there's no built in
default um uh nons or or um sea surf
protection so that could be really cool
so in my in my you know WordPress
plug-in assessing journey I found uh a
couple scenarios where um we have CES
surf but that c surf is uh is limited to
a post request right they're using you
know dollar signore post or something
like that to pull user input yeah
um in those scenarios obviously we're in
the era of Sam site cookies um and and a
lot of times cross-site requests are not
sending uh cookies anymore because of
those same site defaults implemented by
Chrome um this is something that I
wanted to ask you and I'm not I'm not
sure if you got the chance to look it up
before we before we uh got on the call
but do you know if there's any way to
trigger a session refresh in WordPress
via sees surf because here's here's the
approach that we normally take when
doing sees surf in a bug boundy context
is you you find your CES surf you get it
validated you validate with a two-minute
post um you know there's there's a
two-minute exception to the same site
lacks default stuff right um and which
I'm not even sure if if WordPress uses
same site lacks by
doesn't use it doesn't use same site
cookies by default you're stuck with
whatever Chrome sticks on there and I've
honestly never had it be a problem I've
never run into any problems executing a
CES surf on a WordPress site okay wow
that's great so maybe maybe they've got
it even turned off but um one of the
things that that you know Chrome should
be protecting it within a two after the
two-minute window of login um but it
could be you know reing the session
that's something that I need to kind of
look into is like I wonder if there's
some core Gadget that we can use to send
a cerve to refresh the user's session
and then get that cookie reset and
refresh that two-minute window uh do you
know anything sort of like that not off
the top of my head though no okay that's
something that like there's a heartbeat
there's the heartbeat but that actually
does use a you know different nons every
time does it it uses an not okay got
well not different nons every time but
it does use an not so right right and
that's the that's the funny thing about
the whole nons related thing too is like
it's not a number used once in this
scenario it's like that's that's kind of
hilarious you get two each one lasts 48
or you get one that lasts 24 hours and
then it's still valid for another okay
it's valid for 24 hours and then they
generate a new one for the next 24 hours
but the old one still works for that
period so okay great right love that
yeah and I did look into the
implementation of that when I first you
know started deep diving WordPress stuff
and it's pretty solid um you know they
they essentially take your session token
it's tied to your session so even if
it's from a different session you can't
use use it um you know they take your
user ID your session token the current
time stamp a bunch of other things hash
it and then you know use it as the nons
switch is kind of a pain in the ass but
you know it's good to see good good sea
surf protection in place you know as
long as the developers use it which is
what you know is a little bit iffy in
these scenarios I it's pretty easy to
set up but yeah a lot of elers don't use
it or try to use it for Access Control
so so I guess while we're on that topic
what are the what is a non in the comp
uh context of Wordpress I guess we've
kind of already covered that it's It's A
Cerf protection it stands for number
used once but it's not really used once
it's just kind of like A Cerf protection
and what are the functions that we need
to be on the lookout
for to to see for if they're verifying
the non or not uh check admin refer is
one of them uh let's see WP verify kns
yeah so check admin refer it's kind of
weirdly named again because it doesn't
actually check the refer I don't think
right it doesn't
that would be a terrible way to do
things
yeah oh my gosh and so then instead it
checks the nons that's passed into it
and nones in WordPress they have some
sort of action associated with them
right uh I mean if you're talking about
uh W create or create nons um no I mean
like that little what is that little
string that's passed into them like it's
like uh like often times it'll be like
the name of the action that nons is
supposed to be associated with oh yeah
no yeah you can create different nonces
for different
there's a default you know general for a
user but uh most plugins will have you
know different nonces for different
purposes um some plugins will just have
one plugin Global non and that's
especially bad if you're using it for
Access Control but yeah you can
basically create you know nonces for
different purposes nonces specific to
use cases okay so there there are
various actions that can be associated
with nones yeah and and so I can't take
you know a non even if it's associated
with my account for you know changing my
user profile and then use it in the
specific function uh you know on the
specific plugin because more than likely
they're going to have some sort of
action that's associated with that nons
yeah it's not even really an action so
much as just a label a label okay yeah
it's just like this nonsense for this
that nonsense for that for this user so
gotcha so so and and those those can
have value I guess in some ways uh for
an attacker because if you're able to
leak nonsense that are associated with
specific values yes um from an access
control perspective and then the that
that function is solely relying on nonis
for Access Control then we can start we
can bypass Access Control in those
scenarios right exactly yeah so so I
guess the attack in that scenario would
be like let's say that they're
generating Ann on admin nit right I
think this is similar to the scenario we
just talked about with Elementor um and
and you know it's generating a nons and
then it's sticking it in the response
from admin and it which we know that
anybody can access right um and then you
go there you get that nons and then you
you craft the request to trigger a
specific code path um and the they're
only relying on you know a
non the the access to that non whether
you can access that nons or not assuming
that you can't access that nons you know
in a scenario where you actually can
that is a is a vulner you know a code
pattern that I've seen that can result
in vulnerabilities is that would you say
that that's fairly common that is
incredibly common you should never
assume that someone can't access an non
never use an as the sole form of Access
Control uh we'll get into some other
stuff but you know we were going to talk
about uh Menu Pages but a lot of the
ways that uh WordPress or a lot of the
ways that plugins uh try to protect
nones is by checking which page the user
is currently accessing and only
displaying the nons if it's on that
particular page but there are ways to
mess with that oh really can can you
tell me a little bit about that uh yeah
so uh WordPress uses a global called
page now to determine which admin page
you're on um oh and is this a part of
core yes oh really interesting huh yeah
and on some configurations I believe
it's enginex might have gotten a little
trickier recently uh but on some
configurations because it uses PHP self
you can basically you know do one page
at an old bite and then do the page you
want to think you're
on interesting and then that that might
generate some other nons for you yeah
assuming well what would be the
Assumption then in that scenario that
that page does not have access controls
that prevent your user from well then
you could just access it in the first
Pace well let's say um all subscribers
if you're not running woocommerce for
instance uh can access the profile page
uh so you know you're subscriber you log
in the profile page uh but let's say the
nons only shows up on an admin page for
uh you know XYZ plugin so you go to the
profile page and uh add an N bite add
you know admin.php
ah so it's still coming from an admin
Source but then it's perceived to be a
different page yeah and it's tricky to
pull off like you know it's a fairly
rare case but it does happen wow that's
really cool is this is this uh uh this
is under the the weird WordPress [__]
section of our this under the weird
WordPress [__] section is there is there
a um is there do you have any um I guess
documented places where this has been
exploited uh yeah uh you know Mark Mass
I think he works for automatic now yeah
uh I'll add it to the notes at some
point but uh I believe it was in
a oh yeah there was a uh you know backup
download in our updraft plus a while
back that uh that took advantage of this
no way that that sounds really cool I
yeah definitely go ahead and grab that
and put it in the dock I would love to
see that afterwards and for any of you
guys that are also interested in looking
at it um that's something that we'll
we'll Link in the description uh because
that that's seems like a really valuable
way to get your hands on nones and and
unfortunately we see a lot of plugins do
this this thing where they don't do any
authorization checks uh we'll kind of
cover this a little bit later well
actually I guess we'll just cover it now
the the the way WordPress does off
checks is they do
can uh current user can calls which is a
function that comes apart of of
Wordpress and it and it accepts a
capability right and that capability is
associated with different types of users
yeah it'll also accept a role but that's
uh generally considered core practice uh
it's pretty old I I was gonna ask you
about that actually because I saw that
the other day and I was like what the
heck administrator is not a capability
what is does this code even work it
actually it's WordPress has a ton of
backward compatibility stuff so wow okay
so it will accept the role as well um
and that's literally pretty much the
primary way like 99.9% of the time
that's how they're doing off checks
right so but there are some plugins that
will not even use that and just rely on
your ability to access the nons for the
access controls which is really like you
mentioned Ram really bad form um so this
any extra tricks that could get get us
access to nones um when they think we
shouldn't be able to get access to nones
extremely valuable um so so that's
that's really rad um also it looks like
that updraft plus thing uh that was not
a non spy pass using that page now it
was okay yeah it was something else I
think we'll find it afterwards and we'll
put it in the notes for the people that
are that are interested all right um so
that that covers a lot of the ad action
stuff there's a lot more to unpack there
though so I just wanted to make you know
our our goal here on critical thinking
we try to get as technical as we can but
at the end of the day it's an audio
medium so you The Listener need to go
and look into this more um or else your
brain's going to forget it and you're
not going to be able to be you know
triggered by this thing in the past um
when you see something that's that's
trilar similar to this so definitely
check out the link in the description um
and figure out how to access these
really weird part of the uh uh WordPress
functionality um with that Ram I want to
have you talk to me a little bit about
something that I don't really even fully
understand still which is the ad filter
functionality which is a little bit
different than ad action yeah ad filter
is basically uh registers an observer uh
and a call back whenever an action
happens so uh you can add a filter that
runs a call back whenever your profile
is updated or post is updated um it
doesn't actually run it until apply
filters uh gets executed but it's
basically a way of setting up different
observers for stuff okay it's a little
clunky but uh yeah the name filter means
that it often gets used to like you know
sanitize stuff do some postprocessing on
content but uh there is also C Mo for
exploitation for instance uh we see a
lot with like update profile
MH like uh you can add a filter on
update profile so it'll run a call back
whenever a user updates the profile and
it accept extra
input interesting so then so then
anybody who can update their own profile
can trigger that that code exactly yeah
okay okay so add filter WordPress
built-in function that allows you to
create callbacks on specific actions
that occur when apply filter is run
right so apply filter is the trigger uh
add filter is the you know the hook or
whatever yeah and the cool thing is that
it'll actually accept uh not only
built-in WordPress uh actions but also
custom actions by plug-in developers so
ah so they can Define their own and and
anytime that action happens they just
run apply filter and then that kicks off
a bunch of I don't know are they async
or they syn they got to be synchronous I
imagine uh they're in a priority but I
believe they are synchronous yes okay
yeah so so synchronous actions that are
correlated with that specific hook
that's interesting so yeah we we have
update profile update post a couple
other things that non-administrative
level users could trigger and that's
result in some you know malicious code
flow occurring where the user can can do
things they shouldn't do very cool I
like that so that that's sort of I guess
when I was sort of looking into
WordPress history that's sort of like
the mid the mid tier you know way back
in in the beginnings of Wordpress time
they were using xmlrpc and stuff like
that for a lot of implementing rout and
implementing um Ajax requests and that
sort of thing then we move to add action
and that whole flow with the admin
ajax.php and we're still a little bit in
that era there's active development
occurring with those functionalities but
then WordPress um implemented this
register rest routes functionality can
you tell me a little bit about that sure
uh so I mean it is uh WordPress rest
routes are super handy what's even
cooler is that you can actually go to uh
WordPress or you know you can go to the
site wp-json and it'll just show you all
the registered restaurants and you can
dig into them and it just gives you a
map of
them you know I think I heard of this
before I think I saw it somewhere in the
super handy is it
PHP just uh go to the site wp-json you
know I think I've got some sort of weird
routing thing hecked up with my Docker
container cuz it's not hting
oh you might have to have pretty permal
link turned on if not you can do uh you
can do uh let's see uh just add uh rest-
route equals uh forward
slash at the end
yes dot
route rest Dash I think it's a
dash
interesting let me see this here it
might be an underscore
is this as a huh dude I'm gonna have to
I'm gonna have to look into this yeah
it's rest underscore route sorry is it
is that as a parameter uh yes restore
route and it'll show you all the name
spaces and you can dig into the names
spaces no way it's amazing
right
what wow okay so we can just hit
slash question mark restore route
equals slash and it will give us access
to this interface wow whoa dude it took
actually so long for this to load
because there was so many of them and my
poor Docker container is overloaded wow
this is like a big Recon dub do I don't
have to be do I have to be authenticated
for this
nope dude Ram this is not good dude why
do they do this uh ease of use I guess I
mean it's definitely one of those things
you'd want in like debug mode mod but I
don't know if you'd really want that in
production I mean like you the rest
routes are it does give you a lot of
info on what's installed you can you can
get access to it anyway you know because
you can just hit the plugins directory
and use enumeration to figure out what
plugins are then look at the you know
read readme.txt and figure out you know
okay what code is running and then look
at that and extract all the rest routes
but this is just so much more convenient
time saer yeah for sure wow uh guys this
is a big this is a big Dub here I'm
going to put this in the uh dude why is
this not under the weird WordPress [__]
section is this I don't know I I grew up
thinking it was normal this is crazy man
uh so I'm going to go ahead and add it
to the weird WordPress [__] section um
that that's a really big dub for anybody
looking at a WordPress site just
literally add the parameter restore
route equals slash and then it just
dumps all of the the uh rest routes
associated with that site that's crazy
okay so so then you know we've got those
we can access them like a normal um API
or whatever but there there's there are
some nuances to that right which is they
fixed the whole no automatic sees surf
protection thing can you tell me a
little bit about that so um if you don't
provide an Nots that's uh again per user
uh to a rest R it will basically assume
that you're
unauthenticated which is uh well if
you're trying to access uh something
that has a permission call back that
returns true or that has a permission
call back that yeah if if it has a set
if it has you can have the permission
call back
uh I guess so the permission call back
is the thing that allows access control
right so if that permission call back
does some sort of like current user can
check or something like that the current
user is going to be not not there
because it's unoff so then you exactly
you know you you you drop it but then if
there's no reference to the current user
in that interface and they're just
assuming that it's secure you know then
then it has no se protection wow okay
all right well hey I mean that's better
than the Ajax stuff the the add action
stuff where there's just no you know
implementation at all that uh that that
runs by default um yeah and you have to
use Ajax to get the uh
ronance oh yeah yeah yeah that that
makes sense and then and then so I guess
let me ask this what would let me give
me just a gut a gut feeling on this what
is the distribution of use right now
between adore action you know wpor Ajax
uncore versus rest routs I want to say
it's still 80% Ajax really no way yeah
and that's the thing as more and more
plugin start bringing resturants online
uh they're making mistakes in their
first implementation so there's a lot of
opportunity for you know seeing plugins
not using best practices on their first
go yeah that that makes sense and
actually I'm gonna I'm gonna keep my my
cards closer to my chest here than I
normally do Ram I know you know about my
WordPress automation because we've
talked about it a little bit but that is
definitely
something I guess since the kickoff in
December uh of the the word fence bani
program I've built some automation stuff
uh that uses
um some let's just say some code parsing
grammar and uh you know that has been
kicking out a lot of vules I think we've
we've identified over over 10 vules from
the automation and we're seeing vules
popping up in real time as developers
push new code it doesn't even support
register rest routes yet so I think
that's going to get bumped up on my
priority list after this find some good
stuff I think I think there could be
some really good stuff there um Okay so
we've got register rest routes that's
another great way to get to be able to
execute code right to be able to trigger
code execution flows on the server side
um do I want to mention the weird
WordPress [__] about this yeah yes
please yeah okay so uh you know how you
know most rest apis um if if it accepts
get as a method then you have to use
Query string parameters with WordPress
you can put Json on the body and and get
as the method and it'll just parse
it it'll it'll
parse it wait so it allows for the body
of there allows for a get request to
have a request body yes it's not parsing
like you're not putting the Json like in
the queer parameter and then question
mark and then like a blob of Json no
it'll it'll read the entire raw post
body for all request methods what the
heck so and then if you use functions
like I I can't even really wrap my head
around that so then if you use functions
like WP
query that's like they because it's not
going to show up in dollar signore get
or dollar signore post will it no it
uses uh PHP input
oh PHP but or I um would it would it
show up in request do you think I mean
it would probably yeah ah dollar signore
request that could be interesting okay
so WordPress
parses actually no request has to use um
request has to use um either form
encoded or um M form encoded yeah so
yeah no it wouldn't show up in any of
those interesting so it's got to be it's
got to use the PHP uh you know the the
input uncore post input underscore get
but that's still really really pivotal
for for ways that one you know WordPress
will parse the that data and then that
that's that's the kind of sneaky [__]
you guys got to know about to be able to
pop crazy bugs is like oh I can they're
not expecting me to be able to give Json
input to this specific function because
I'm doing it under a get request you
know on that one for a while no no no
doubt in my mind that there's some you
know some code out there that's like all
right you know a get request will allow
a post request no and then they're
sharing logic and you can send body
along with a get request and it's going
to screw their whole their whole
mechanism that's crazy that's really
good thank you for that Ram this is
exactly the stuff that I wanted when you
know for you to to talk about when you
came on here repress is full stuff like
this yeah dude and and that's why I've
been kind of finding that out over the
past like month or two as I've been kind
of geeking out about it um and and the
the crazy thing to me about it too is
that it's everywhere man WordPress is
literally on every single attack surface
you can possibly think of like every
company has a blog or like three blogs
they got an engineering blog they got a
marketing blog they got a companywide
you know press release blog and so
there's so many opportunities out there
and people are installing plugins that
are like 500 installs or something like
that and using it on their you know main
site stuff that hasn't really been
audited and and stuff like that so
there's a lot of there's a lot of value
here for um specifically for bug bounty
hunters that want to
find vulnerabilities using white you
know white box code code
review if I were going if I were going
to U make a recommendation a lot of the
low install count authentication plugins
are full
of dude that's terrifying man they're
below the they're below our C our
current scope requirements but man
there's there's a lot of stuff in there
unless you get unless you get the um uh
what is it like Elite status or
something like that right then it drops
to like a thousand or something I think
the requirement does yeah if you end up
with the elite status and you know
that's that's not that hard to get just
you know keep on putting in good bugs
I'm I'm well on my way I'll get there
eventually um so I'm excited for that uh
all right so next thing we've got on the
list here as we're kind of going through
WordPress syncs I mean uh sources still
excuse me um and then we're going to
talk about syns at some point too but we
got to get our sources in place so we
know where our data is coming from and
we could start tracking code flows okay
so um we mentioned earlier
uh page related code right um so this is
using built-in WordPress functions like
adore submenu unor page this allows us
to I I assume Define little pages on the
left side in the admin panel and how do
how does that work and how could a a
person hook functionality into that uh
so if it's done right you can't okay um
WordPress basically lets you register
Pages um and it performs a capability
check during the page registration and
then has a call back to whatever
function Ren renders the page um but you
know not all
plugins only use that to call that
function uh some of them will also call
those functions using you know admin
Ajax using admin in it uh and it'll
perform a check to see what the current
page is to see if uh you know you're
supposed to be there WordPress does
actually use the um page get parameter
to verify what page you're supposed to
be on so really so wait tell me tell me
about that what is that what is that so
in the query parameter in the get query
parameter you can say quer question mark
page equals something and then it will
yeah that's what the register page uh or
register menu basically does is uh it'll
basically register that page as the
thing that calls that
function interesting hold on maybe I'm
uh uh my my uh my Docker container is is
being slow because I've got too many too
many plugins installed I feel you man
I've got like I just disable them most
of the time classic problems I yeah I
need to go back and disable them um I'm
gonna log in really quick and see if I
if I am actually remembering properly
what you're talking ah yeah because then
then you've got that and then there's
the page parameter okay okay I see yeah
so that that is also used to show you
know what as sort of a source of Truth
in those scenarios to see what page
you're on specifically and that that's
pretty hard to mess with um for the
actual page parameter uh you know the
thing we talked about earlier accepted
but yeah yeah interesting and and so
yeah wp-admin admin.php question mark
page equals whatever will trigger
various stuff I just went to this page
and an alert popped because he already
had something in there my my buddy's
working on something it sounds like he
got it pop that's great um I try to use
different messages for my alerts so I
know which one it's actually from so
yeah that's smart Ram we're we're not
all as smart as you at that because
you're just like wait where is this
where is this popping up from that's
great all right um so then the last
little thing that we wanted to talk
about from from an input perspective is
short codes um as I'll try to give it a
little bit of a summary of that and then
you can fix it so essentially short
codes are a um a way for people who have
the the ability to write posts normally
I don't know if you can use them yeah
contributors and yeah um those are roles
in WordPress by the way you've got
subscriber that's the lowest level
permission all the way up to
administrator with
editor
author contributor in that order yep
descending yep it's uh administrator
editor author contributor and
realistically editors can become admins
at any point if they really want to
because they have filtered HTML access
so right okay and then you can just at
that point you can just input HTML
anywhere and next time an admin comes in
there hijack their session into whatever
you want exactly yeah gotcha so editor
is pretty much administrator level
permissions anyway it's one of those we
trust you enough that if you really
wanted to yeah yeah gotcha yeah don't be
Editor to anyone you trust yeah that
makes sense so short codes are a way for
contributors normally I guess authors as
well to embed specific functionality in
posts that a lot of times it's
functionality that's inside of plugins
and cont forms that kind of oh yeah
contact forms too yeah for sure and then
and then there's like
um I think the syntax is like a square
bracket and then some text it's almost
like an HTML tag but it us code actually
you remember that oh B oh yeah dude I
haven't heard that name in I haven't
heard that in a long time special
implementation of HTML yeah this is back
in the form days on when I was on hack
forms or something like that it's crazy
um so yeah kind of like that and then
you're triggering various pieces of
functional how does this hook into um
plug-in code so uh plugins will
basically register short codes uh and
the attributes those short codes accept
uh it is really wide open because yeah
yeah uh and WordPress has a short code
parsing RX that scans through posts
looking for short codes and if it's Bots
one that has been registered it goes
here you go run this function and do
whatever wow and is there any built-in
controls there for sanitization in in
attributes or anything like that or
nope lovely love that yeah I want to say
like more than half of the actual uh in
scope vulnerabilities we got over that
over that period where short code cross
scripting wow and and I imagine that has
limited limited well you know I guess
it's contributor it's contributor to I
mean honestly you're going to have a
much better chance of someone you know
pulling off a credential stuffing attack
for a contributor than you are for an
actual contributor to want to go bad
that's true yeah so compromising
compromising uh contributor account and
then you know I guess depending on the
location as well where they can trigger
it you it could be a no user interaction
cross- Aid scripting right you know
because it triggers somewhere the admin
would go naturally or it could be a user
interaction yeah excuse me storex assess
because you still have to get them to
navigate to a specific page where your
payload will fire I mean realistically
if it's a page that we're going to land
on anyway we don't consider that user
interaction okay gotcha yes and then
here's the thing since contributor posts
have to be reviewed by an editor or an
administrator in order to be published
they're going to see that post no matter
what so
interesting that's a that's good to know
so so if you can so actually yeah
there's a decent amount of impact then
and and then of course we all know like
admin admin um xss in WordPress results
in you being able to modify the the
plugin source code you can create new
admin users you can uh you can edit you
know Plugin or theme Source all sorts of
stuff you can pull results in RC wow
that's very interesting that that's cool
and but and I guess might this might be
more of a a Chloe oriented uh question
but the the way that word fence still
rates that in a well I guess stored xss
is rated a little bit higher than
reflected xss and yes and the big reason
behind that is just because uh uh
vulnerabilities require genuine user
interaction including including SE surf
I mean that's going to H they're going
to have to be personalized they're going
to have to be targeted you're not going
to have as much luck as something on
like a big platform where yeah all a URL
everyone expects to see that makes a a
lot of sense unauthenticated xss too you
know like there's lots of ways that you
can pivot that um pivot that but yeah
there there's definitely if you've got a
authenticated reflected xss there's
going to be a little bit of a tricky
tricky piece to that that is the value
is so yeah for sure um all right so
that's mostly mostly covered our sources
I'll just go ahead and run through them
real quick because I know we kind of hit
the ground running pretty quickly for
the audience um we've got add action
that allows you to hook various callback
functions and Associated them or hook
into specify callback functions for
specific hooks there we go um that you
can trigger so for example there's an
admin in it uh hook and that can be
triggered by navigating to pretty much
any admin endpoint um and that will
trigger call back code so that's a great
place to look for vulnerabilities
there's an admin action uh call back
that just looks for an action parameter
anywhere you're on the on the admin page
and that's fun that doesn't get used as
much but when it does get used it's
usually used poorly great love that I
love patterns like that if they do use
it it uses it's used poorly so admin
uncore action admin uncore um or
admin poost I believe is also one of
them and as well since it's an older
pattern love that um and then there's
wpor Ajax uncore and then some text
which will allow you to trigger that um
and there's the no priv versions of
those as well so that's a great way to
trigger um uh some code that you want to
run uh those are all vulnerable to Sea
Surf and O well I guess some of them
have o by default but some of them don't
um and so those are great places to look
for vones in addition we've got the ad
filter functionality right um and that's
that's where various actions are
occurring and then uh those you're
specifying callbacks for those actions
so if you're able to trigger that action
for example updating your profile then
you may be able to run that code which
may have a vulnerable um aspect to it
yeah one thing I would recommend
strongly is uh just if you can get X
debug set up on a Docker container and
just you know step through some basic
Ajax actions you'll get a much better
sense for just that's a idea that's
that's a great idea I haven't gone as
far as to hook up a debugger to it but I
have modified the PHP code directly and
just put die statements in there you
know I've got a u I've got a Docker
configuration that has XD buug working
on it if you want send it over great we
should we should we should do that and
we should update the um the the docker
container script that I created for the
campaign uh to have some of that stuff
on there because that would be really
that'd be really helpful to the to the
researchers I think um and then from
there we've got the rest routes stuff um
that it has some sea surve protection in
it by default and some Access Control uh
on it by default but because it's newer
technology uh you know it's being used
less and or being used for the first
time which is triggering vulnerabilities
so that's another great place to look um
and then we've got co uh page related
registration so uh add submenu page or
something like that not as great of a
place to look and then short codes which
apparently is a great place to look for
contributor plus uh stored xss do that
doeses that about wrap it all
that more or less wraps it all up we
didn't really cover XML RPC but most
most of the use case for that is
honestly credential stuffing because it
lets you fire off a bunch of
authentication requests really quickly
yeah you can batch them right yeah yeah
yeah so that's that's helpful for like
maybe identifying contributor level uh
accounts from which to take over the
whole server uh if you're actually doing
like a bug Bounty or a pentest or
something like that sometime I will I
will throw out there sometimes programs
do not like credential stuffing and or
trying to find that sort of thing on bug
bounding programs so RPC use cases are
not well suited for real bug hunting
because they're like Nia service
credential stuffing stuff that you
wouldn't really use unless you were on
like an actual red team engagement right
right so and I know there are programs
out there that will accept stuff like
that um especially I I I shouldn't say
especially only if you found valid
credentials um but program by program so
make sure you're not overstepping the
balance um with that we'll go ahead and
move over to top syncs for WordPress
um and let me just go see in here we
already kind of covered capabilities we
already kind of covered filters we
already kind of covered leaking
nonces um I'm just kind of going through
the the wp the WordPress Concepts
section here to make sure we are hitting
everything um yeah let's go ahead and
and jump right into the top s then I
don't think we have anything else we
need to to um sort of talk about from
from the weird WordPress Concepts uh
perspective so regarding top syns
obviously we've got a lot of PHP related
stuff which is mostly going to be uh
something that the listeners need to go
sus out for themselves um but that's
going to be stuff like unlink is file
file exists file get contents require uh
Slash include or anything like that
which could result in RFI or lfi um old
standbys like eval exact pass through
whatever yeah exactly just like those um
you know these are things that we're not
really focused on in this context
because we're mostly focusing on
WordPress related stuff for this episode
as we have the man Ram here who we can
ask about any WordPress related stuff so
as far as sys go that are WordPress
included functions what should we be
looking for Ram uh one of the big ones
is update option uh and the reason for
that is that WordPress options include
things like the default role and whether
or not users can register if you can set
the default world to administrator and
set users and register on then you can
register an admin user I do want to
offer a word of warning I have had some
trouble getting these to work lately and
I've been looking for the code trying to
figure out how they're sanitizing them
and uh so I wouldn't necessarily rely on
it you know test it at your own risk but
if you can get it to work then that's a
very uh powerful exploit okay so so that
scenario would be I imagine update
option looks something like key and then
value right that sort of thing um yeah
update option users can register value
one sure sure sure and then and then one
of the things that I've seen a little
bit more often is you don't get to
specify the key and the value but you
can specify just the value and that will
that's helpful in a tax like C surf for
access control stuff because it can
modify the options of the Plugin or the
or the website the big thing you get
from that is xss what we see a lot of is
uh update options uh being used for
things like API keys and not escaping or
validating the API key on output so you
can put like an xss payload in that API
key option and it'll ech out Echo out
and an administrator V visits the uh
page where they set the API key that's
great that that is actually the bug that
triggered when uh when I went to open up
that that that page to check what you
were talking about um buddy of mine
who's actually been on on the Pod before
Kodi um he he found one uh where it was
you he was able to se surf an update
option and then that update option would
then get triggered on the page so on the
admin page so we actually did this cool
exploit where you and it's in yall's
inbox so no I think I remember this one
yeah yeah yeah so so you you go to the
page and um and you know you click the
link and it does like it opens up a new
tab it submits a form to a new tab right
and then on the old tab it does a
timeout uh and after you know two
seconds or whatever it'll redirect the
user to that page which was now Poisoned
With The the crossy scripting payload
because of the form opening up on the
new tab right so it's like this time
sync thing too nice um which is a really
cool piece of that exploit uh so that
that is definitely something that I've
seen and actually happens I'd imagine
quite a bit um and and then there's also
I think Rim the the use case of like
okay well maybe it can't it can't be put
in an xss um you sort of scenario but
it's Al it's also just updating the
site's settings so from an access
control perspect perspective site URL
you can change the blog URL you can get
it to redirect home advertising site you
can yeah you can pull all sorts of stuff
or Plugin specific functionality like
yeah you know hey maybe we can set a
value for a specific option and that has
very high plug-in relative impact right
oh yeah no uh I mean like some plugins
allow you to set which roles are allowed
to use which functionality so you'll
have like a file manager plugin that's
restricted to add by default but if you
can set the option to allow subscribers
to use the file manager plugin then you
have RC
that's great so update options is a big
one for sure any other ones we should be
aware of um for update options or are we
moving on no no for within the I'm sorry
within the syncs section so WordPress
related syncs with update option is a
WordPress uh just to be clear for the
listeners update option is a WordPress
function that will you will see in the
code that could all alert you to a
sync see we're moving on to the next
sync uh one of the ones that we see a
lot is uh add post update post delete
post trash post
um if you can add post and it doesn't
sanitize the count content on the way in
or if you can update a post and it
doesn't sanitize the content on the way
in uh then you have xss again ah okay so
you you specify the content of that or I
imagine you know for delete trash Post
Yeah you can delete them or get rid of
them and that sort of thing another
weird WordPress [__] thing if you trash
a post twice it permanently permanently
deletes it oh interesting so if you can
double trigger it it actually has some
serious impact
which uh yeah you could do that with
that same setup that I was talking about
exactly because you could trigger it in
a new tab that would delete it once and
then trigger it in the in the main tab
again and that would delete it for the
second time which is gone interesting
that's Ram thank you very much sir I I
love this stuff this I can the heart is
beating quickly uh yeah I love that
um that's great so and and I imagine
also there's a little bit and this is
something that I don't understand so
maybe you can enlighten me a little bit
on this some users have the capability
to inject unfiltered HTML right correct
like uh editors and administrators yep
editors and administrators that you
mentioned earlier and so I guess if you
had the ability to C Surf and then
affect the contents of an ad post and do
that for an administrator or an editor
then you could use that functionality to
trigger accss inside that post because
of the person's your SE surfing's
unfiltered HTML injection capability you
could it uh doesn't come up very often
because it's fairly rare for a post
update to have uh Nots protection or
access or to have access control but no
non protection usually it lacks both or
it has both ah okay yeah and the default
way of updating posts does use non
checks but you know some plugins will do
some weird stuff where they update
manually without going through all the
uh motions gotcha no that that that
makes sense yeah that's one that's one
of the things that's a little bit tricky
for me is about WordPress 2 is like you
can trigger sometimes serers side code
that you your current user doesn't have
access to do at the at the WordPress
level but it won't it won't do it's not
like the the WordPress system itself is
running as you know system or something
like that it's still always applying
that that WordPress level um I guess
capability or role assessment to yeah
those functions which makes sense
um okay so the next one here is update
user meta talk to me a little bit about
that so uh user meta uh there's your
role your capabilities those are all
stored in uh your user metadata okay so
uh you can set your capabilities to
administrator and then you are an
administrator okay so so if we were able
to find a place where we could update
arbitrary user
metadata GG exactly and uh one of the
ways that we one of the places we see
that happen a lot is with membership
plugins from what I can remember pretty
much every single membership plugin
we've ever analyzed has at some point in
its life cycle had the problem where you
were able to set your role upon
registration you love to see it setting
the wp capabilities user Meda key wow
yeah that that makes sense so that's
that's something that we can particular
they look into is like and I imagine
that's a little bit more helpful on like
the action that's associated with
updating your profile or like some sort
of filter based thing that triggers when
you are taking some action like updating
your profile yeah that that's one of the
places update profile comes in handy
nice um so a coule m man I have to say I
love it when the guests come on here and
they do a great job preparing on the
dock like that just warms the heart like
and the episodes always turn out so much
better because there's so many things
you know that I don't know that I want
to know I mean I forgotten half this
stuff I had to brush up on it no it's
great and then and then you put it in
the dock and then I'm like oh that is
something I want to know and then I ask
about it and it makes me happy so um the
the move uploaded file unzip related
functionality tell me a little bit about
that oh uh I mean I guess to some extent
that's basic uh PHP stuff but WordPress
has its own upload hand
Handler which plugins should use so if
you see them not using that that's a
danger sign interesting okay
so uh if it uses move uploaded file uh
if it uses an unzip uh I mean that's you
know again it's normal PHP stuff but if
it doesn't specifically look check file
types within the zip then you have an
opportunity interesting yeah anytime
anytime you're dealing with zips this is
a pretty General web application hacking
thing is like if they're dealing with
zips there's going to be some weird [__]
that can happen there you you do zip
slip you can do you know all sorts of
file extension hidden files that don't
get deleted from directories like all
sorts of weird stuff you can do with
that absolutely so that's always a good
one and then I see you also put here
wpor remote unor getet um which is a
great a great one and I imagine that's
often used as a sync for ssrf absolutely
absolutely yeah uh wpr remote get is the
built-in WordPress
uh uh server side request functionality
it uses curl or whatever it has
available but uh you can use it for ssrf
if you're on an ec22 box with imds or is
it idms I can never
remember one of idms uh you can grab the
ec2 box credentials and uh then you own
the Box yeah dude I love that man I I I
I saw earlier I I was snooping around
the the bugs I try not to Snoop around
the bugs too much before people come on
because you know I like to be surprised
on the on on the podcast but I did see
you pwned some box with that so I I it
was my own box but yeah well yeah but
you know it still counts every every
WordPress is is very often launched in
in AWS so that's good to see and the
other thing is that a lot of
configurations don't use idms V to so uh
and a lot of WordPress plug-in develop
don't really take into account that ssrf
is a thing there's some plugins whose
entire functionality basically depends
on at the very least blind ssrf so you
know yeah 100% I've seen that often as
well ssrf is is definitely becoming more
well known in primary web app circles
but I imagine that hasn't trickled down
fully to Wordpress plugins and sort of
peripheral environments like that that's
that's good um so let's talk a little
bit now about Echo as a sync right
anybody who's familiar with PHP knows
that Echo as a sync will Echo something
onto the screen it will print on onto
the the page the HTML that's being
outputed um WordPress has a lot of
escaping mechanisms for various it does
some of them are very good okay so can
you talk to me a little bit about some
common mistakes that you see in escaping
within a uh a WordPress environment that
results in xss oh uh I actually almost
added this to the vulnerabilities but uh
you'll have you know you'll have the
function Escape part of it and then run
s printf on the outside of the escape
and uh wait wait wait say say one more
time you'll have it Escape part of it
yeah it'll have Escape part of it and
then you'll have run s print F around
the escape and oh no yeah yeah that
one's fun you'll you'll see those sort
of things and and actually you know
later later this week we'll record I'm
not sure what order we'll release these
but at sometime soon you'll be uh
thinking listeners will be listening to
an episode about vulnerable code
patterns which was inspired a lot by
reviewing a lot of the source code of
Wordpress plugins um and that's always
always a funny you know piece that you
see where they they try to sanitize
stuff but they just do it a little bit
off you know and and there's some common
patterns you can find that will help you
find bones in any language based off of
that sort of thing um but there's
there's I guess The wpor KES related
functions uh it stands for a strip evil
evil Scripts got it's pretty solid um
it's complicated it's reject based it's
very slow uh which is why they don't run
on absolutely everything yeah but it
does a decent job of you know cleaning
up uh basically any HTML tag from any
unsafe attributes but you know it has to
be a complete HTML tag it has to know
it's an HTML tag in order to remove
those attributes so that's where we run
into stuff like um short code based
crossy scripting because it runs the
ksas on just the attributes before it
adds them to the HTML tag gotcha so this
is something that actually is used to
parse HTML yeah there's like yeah yeah
that's not a great idea that's not a
great idea so that that's something that
where they're expecting HTML and a lot
of times also they'll be expecting just
normal input and they'll use this
function sanitize text field which I
think is is pretty bulletproof like
there's not much you can do about that
right sanitized text field also doesn't
Escape attributes if they're being added
separately so um it'll it'll kill any
tags you have but if you know you have
tag and you have control over the
attribute from a source then uh
sanitized text field isn't going to so
you may be able to ah and that's so if
it's being inject injected into an
attribute it won't escape the double
quote so you can escape out of the
attribute Define your own attribute like
onload or you know on air or something
like that trigger JS through that yeah I
I honestly I should have brought that up
but yeah yeah it just didn't come up
until you mentioned it yeah no you're
good you're good that's what this
section's for so so that's great so then
so we got to understand you know what
what parts of the app and I know there's
functions like Escape at oh yeah it's
you added it right here to the doc
Escape at that are specifically used for
escaping attributes so when you're
looking at this code you kind of got to
get your brain to be like a machine and
say okay where's the context did they
use the right function context function
if they're using Escape URL on some
something that's not a URL there might
be a way to get around it if they're
using Escape js on something that's you
knowl or something yeah then there might
be a way around it interesting very cool
so the the naming convention is I should
pretty be should be pretty much similar
to the context in which that that string
is used so that's something to be on the
lookout for yeah um tell me about this
eore or underscore e thing what is that
so WordPress has a lot of uh translation
capabilities uh there's a lot of
websites that will show content in
multiple languages just by setting the
language parameter soore e Echoes out
the text or the translation of the text
if one is available for the requested
Language basic most of the time most
sites don't actually use translations so
it's basically just Echo uh but it it
won't show up if you're just searching
for Echo interesting okay so that's
another sort of echo equivalent of sorts
in the WordPress environments that we
need to be familiar with very cool
so and you can also uh if you have you
know some sort of limited file upload uh
you could potentially upload some uh
translations malicious translations with
uh cross-site scripting payloads and set
the language interesting for those wait
so so you need we would need to be able
to upload what you need to be able to
upload uh translation files I forget
what the extension is but so there's
some there's some maybe
non-administrative not not always
associated with administ functionality
that allows you to update translate
files and then you may by default it's
admin only but uh you know it some
things perform you know they use a block
list instead of an allow list or they
use so you get some of those uh
translation files uploaded youting that
that's a good you know path because like
if you're working with a plugin that
does translation in particular then
maybe there could be some access control
stuff and then okay you think well all
right maybe I can affect the translation
but what does that really do it gets
gets xss exactly um so that that's
that's good to know very cool um and and
so then moving on from xss to and
obviously blind xss is a big thing in in
um in WordPress environment as well so
that's something that uh sort of we got
triggered from last week Ben started
talking a ton about um blind xss and now
my brain has just been spinning about
blind xss yeah just assume the xss and
WordPress is blind and will work and it
probably will that's great now that that
that's good um so moving on to SQL I
syncs um they have a pretty good wrapper
around SQL stuff in in WordPress it's
wpdb uh prepare normally is what's being
used um what are some problems with that
that we can be on the look out for when
we're auditing WordPress plugins well
the biggest problem is uh developers
that don't use it at all um but I okay
you know as as you mentioned uh
preparing part of the uh SQL State SQL
quy but uh concatenating it with an
unprepared portion and then uh actually
running the query so that there's so
that part of it's not prepared uh we do
see that on occasion um there is a sort
of backward compatibility
uh issue with WTB prepare where uh if
instead of percent s for a string it'll
do like labeled strings like percent One
S uh then it won't add quotes to it so
you can run like character-based uh
equal
injection ooh interesting so if you so
it doesn't ah maybe that's because it
doesn't know it's a string it does know
it's a string it just it doesn't it does
know it's a string but because of the
label it doesn't treat it the same uh
there's some WordPress developer doc on
it that just says due to backwards
compatibility so what the heck Ram are
you is this something that's known by
people or are you just dropping like a
core a WordPress core SQL zero day on
critical thinking podcast right now n no
core doesn't use this practice but uh
they just support it in case someone
else does wow that's that's weird man uh
okay so so they've got that
functionality and it won't put in the
double quotes so you might be able to
escape out of that very interesting um
also I you can escape out of single
quotes if you're using a gbk character
set using multi-b encoding but that
almost never happens so I yeah
interesting uh what do is there some
character in that language that is cor
effectively a single quote yeah yeah
it's real old it's been around since
like 2006 it just almost never comes up
because I've never seen a site using
that character set oh and it has to use
that character set in the database yeah
the database okay yeah that's pretty
rare but but that makes me think though
you know maybe there's some you know
websites that are using specific
character sets that
are foreign foreign for and that could
be a good place to do some you know
WordPress related research that that
could be cool yeah I should I should
nerd there's a there's a guy that came
on the Pod um uh I guess probably a
couple months back now this is very much
obsessed with uh character character set
related stuff so I should I should nerd
snipe him with that that'd be good that
stuff hurts my brain man it's
complicated he dropped a really good
blog post though that I still haven't
got found the time to read on which is
essentially like actually I've got it
right here it's literally right in my
bookmark bar the absolute the absolute
minimum every software developer
absolutely positively must know about
unic coding character sets is the name
of the of No Excuses it says at the end
I think I might have read that one
actually that's a great that's a great
article I'll I'll uh if you've read it
you know I'm sure I'm sure it's got a
lot of value to it and Matias mentioned
that um you know he endorses it as well
so that's that's another one we'll link
I I'll go ahead and uh sorry Richie the
the editor I'm G to you're going to have
a really long uh description for this
episode because there's so many things
to link but I'll put that in the doc and
it'll be waiting for you guys in the
description when you go to read that um
and and so the actual things that going
back to to Wordpress um the things that
actually trigger SQL related statements
are wpdb query or get row right get row
there there's a number of other
functions uh update you can you know you
can do time based seq injection
injection on updates or deletes those
are kind of a pain to deal with yeah I
imagine so yeah um so but we need to be
looking for direct injection into query
and get row or can catenation with
prepare or some sort of label-based uh
print F like yeah I'd honestly put the
label based one in the weird [__]
WordPress does because it's pretty rare
we were just like that blew my mind when
I found out about it so I had to mention
it yeah no that's that's that's exactly
the stuff we want to know about and and
that's the kind of stuff you want to
hear about on a podcast and then be like
you know two years down the road you
know when your brain has trapped that
little piece of information deep you're
like oh wait a second I thought I heard
something about that and then you Google
it and you find it and then you you know
pop the bug so that's the kind of stuff
we're going for for sure um one of the
things that that uh my menty actually
brought up as he was doing some some
WordPress uh uh plug-in assessment was
Escape SQL being used in conjunction
with non-quoted strings so uh in those
scenarios as well you can trigger sqli
right correct uh if there's no quotes to
escape then you can just use uh
character based injection right and and
you're not you don't really even need to
break out of any string related contexts
no no double Quotes no single quotes
anything like that so the use a lot of
people just blindly trust um Escape
Escape SQL um I remember my first
security job we used to uh patch stuff
uh using AE escape squel and then I
found out that it wasn't enough and I
was like oh no what am I doing I've made
some mistakes yeah I can I was a PHP
developer actually it was my first
software engineering job and I I winse
when I think back on the code that I
wrote in those
days but yeah I think this is
particularly one of the things I wanted
to call out here is this is particularly
interesting when in context of
uh dealing with integers that and
they're being a type confusion because
in in in WordPress environment you know
you you can say hey when you're doing a
SQL query with a specific integer you
know you can put it in there and you can
say you know x equals whatever without
having to use the double quotes um so if
they're assuming that XYZ argument
that's being pulled from the query
parameters is a integer then and they
insert it that way then it it could be
very vulnerable to this if you just give
it a string instead and manipulate the
the SQL statement um yeah we just
actually I think we just published a
really fun type juggling article ah dude
I love those vulnerabilities I gotta go
I gota go consume that um oh also don't
use sanitized XEX fields for SQL uh
proving stuff santiz oh yeah santized X
field that's for XS yeah yeah yeah that
that would that would be that would be
bad that's great I love that um all
right let me see where else we want to
go here um I do want to talk a little
bit about uh WordPress based escalations
and we also want to talk about sort of
deserialization in a WordPress um
context I'm G with that one huh yeah she
there's a lot there um I'm go ahead and
look through here really quickly make
sure we're not this this document has
become pretty chunky so I'm going to
make sure that we're not
um so yeah I guess one of the things
that that is a vulnerability that's only
specifically correlated to Wordpress
that I kind of wanted to bring up is
this whole concept concept of an
arbitrary non leak vulnerability and and
um this is a scenario where you can take
user input and generate a nons for for
any given sort of label right like you
mentioned before um I probably found one
a couple years ago I think it was in uh
one of the Facebook plugins yeah yeah I
read that right up and it it was amazing
and and so essentially what this allows
you the user to do is escalate
privileges in a lot of scenarios where
where nonces are being used as the
access control because they can generate
a valid nons for any label right that's
that's a that's a weird bug that's what
I wanted to make sure that people were
aware of because it it took a second you
know it's only something limited to a to
a um word related context yeah I'm glad
they're as rare as they are well I hope
they're as rare as I think they yeah
yeah well I I did I did poke around a
little bit for them because I needed
them for a chain and and I didn't see a
lot of them so um even gripping through
all you know 800 and something plugins
that are in scope of y's program so you
have a better time trying to find the
kns on like you know an admin page yeah
exactly um so let's see
here you you have some stuff on here
here WP handle upload was that the stuff
that we we talked about before or were
those was that some other tidbit juicy
tidbit of knowledge that I don't want to
miss out on oh uh WP handle upload is
the built-in WordPress file uploading uh
mechanism it runs some pretty decent
mind type checks and file type
validation checks and extension checks
uh but some plugins will put in
overrides to tell it not to test the
file type and or to allow different M
types and uh then you can get away with
some Mischief wow interesting so WP
handle upload that's that's a function
and look at that there's overrides right
there as the secondary parameter yeah I
realistically WordPress has really good
safe defaults for a lot of things and a
lot of developers just don't just turn
them off love
that okay for that yeah that's that's a
great call out thanks for that I'm glad
I'm glad we didn't skip over that um
definitely you know anytime there's and
and I'll share some interesting stuff
with you outside of the Pod because I've
got you know a top a top plugin that
I've been working on recently and
reported some bugs bugs in they have
some really sketchy uh mime extension
check and MIM checking functionality
that literally just doesn't work at all
yeah look for non-standard MIM type
checks and file type checks you you'll
find all sorts of crazy stuff there's Al
and this is like a very well-known
plugin too so I was very surprised um
great well let let's go a little bit
let's dive back in again to the the
weird WordPress [__] section before we
go to pop chains in WP escalations um
there there's oh actually you know what
I think you know yeah we we covered all
these because this is the the page thing
and the great we covered all I we
covered how I don't think we covered how
uh WordPress actually lets you overload
uh the request and uh oh super global
talk to me about that then what is that
so remember how we were talking about
how WordPress uses the page get
parameter to tell you what page is Page
it's on yeah on ADP yeah WordPress
verifi that that's the correct page
therefore the function wouldn't run if
you weren't on that page right right so
a lot of developers will Echo out the
page parameter but they'll use request
instead of get and
WordPress basically smooshes together it
it if there's a post page parameter
it'll stick it in the request page even
if there's also a get page parameter
what if you so if you did a a post to
that page with with the page in the post
body and the page in the query parameter
yes so you use the correct page in the
in the query parameter and you put an
xss payload in the post
parameter and dude that is sneaky man
yeah those that's that's great so
anytime we see echoing of request page
or echoing of request anything when it
should be using get or post then right
that that makes a lot that makes a lot
of sense so there there's some way for
you to sort of Overlook yeah that's
really weird so in request it smooth you
it what is it just like implode them
with a comma or something like that what
does it do so uh PHP by default will
basically uh stick both get and post
into request uh in order of priority but
uh you can change the priority in
php.ini but WordPress will make darn
sure that whatever is in post gets
priority over whatever's in G if it's
the same parameter name no and WordPress
looks at get to decide what page it's in
yes love it I love that little that
little uh discrepancy between the two
this is exactly what we're looking for
that that's great and so in those
scenarios you can trigger xss by
injecting into the post body exactly
it's usually reflected but yeah and and
and we and did we cover um the Json
related we did Cover the Json related
stuff in the body so that's that's great
okay cool yeah with that let's go ahead
and and and move along to pop chains
okay so this is PHP object N I don't
know what pop actually stands for most
people just call him gadgets but I like
pop change because it's fancy hold on I
could have I swear I've read read this
it's it's it says it's like R chain PHP
object po pollution pH PHP
object what the heck why is it escaping
my my head now
uh well that's a little bit
rip the only one that I see is similar
to R ROP chains pop chains allow you to
do whatever um so I guess pop chains
they're they're essentially useful in
these sort of DC serialization scenarios
exactly and actually I've spent funny
funny story I've spent definitely like
40 hours looking for pop chains in
WordPress core um and WordPress uh top
WordPress plugins because I needed it
for a chain there's some pretty good
ones in I want to say TCP to T to PDF
the main problem is that that never ends
up actually you know the class never
ends up actually loaded when you need it
I hate that Ram H that that drives me
nuts so so essentially this for the
listeners um the the scenarios in which
you need this is a is a DC realization
scenario um and specifically this is the
scenario that I was using it with was
when you were using a far based uh uh
deserialization and this is when you can
inject an arbitrary URL into file undor
exists or is file um and what that will
do is if you give it a PHP archive file
doar file it will try to load that file
up and deserialize the metadata
associated with that and um in that
scenario you need sort of a chain of
Gadgets in order to get rce um and to to
be clear This only affects PHP versions
it 7.4 and Below 7.4 and below I think
wasn't it patched in 8.1 I think or
might they might have just it was either
eight or 8.1 yeah yeah eight or 8.1 you
know some some of the if it's in the
sevens you're fine everyone still used
using sub exactly it's the 5.6 of 2024
right great yeah that's that's good um
so you know still still widely used um
but you can use that functionality to
get RC as well so if you you have
arbitrary injection into a uh into a
file underscore exists or is file um any
stat-based uh call in PHP um and so I
found that and I was looking I was like
I need to find a pop chain so I started
going through unfortunately there was
one that was patched in December that
was like blatantly obvious you know that
was real bad that that one was very
obvious and I would have loved to use it
but um in the end I couldn't find one
and there's a bunch of really good
writeups out there like essentially
chaining together just this crazy
massive beautiful flow of functions and
classes and and stuff to trigger these
um these These Chains but essentially
the concept for these is that you need
some class that you can instantiate and
just set the attributes of that class
and then have some function Trigger or
some something being called on that
class like two string or underscore
underscore wake up or underscore
underscore destroy that kicks off a code
flow that eventually allows you to gain
control of the whole application just
from populating the attributes of a
certain class is that accurate Ram that
is better than I could have said it
myself it it's it's it's a cluster man
it's nuts and and you spending time
looking for this is crazy because you're
you're having to reach so deep into all
of these PHP internals of like all right
well what if I treat a cat uh you know a
class like like an array and I'm like
trying to attribute access like the
certain attributes of like this array
but actually it's a class and it's
calling these functions it's it's nuts
so so many interesting things there
we'll link an amazing one um and
WordPress uses uh serialized data
basically everywhere in its internals
and uh built-ins handled that
serialization fairly well but a lot of
plugins seek to emulate it and don't
handle that serialization quite as well
so you'll end up with you know storing
session data as an object in cookies and
yeah that that's that's scary man and
and so yeah that's a great Point Ram so
so cookies is actually probably one of
the the top uh sources for that sort of
DC realization front yeah I'd see so
yeah wow yeah that's good definitely
something to be on the lookout for there
um we also see a lot of like uh settings
import exports functional that's always
that's always a fun source to play with
or even update options probably right
you know there's being there's stuff
being stored in there in a calized
format anyway I I I I just wanted to
talk about this because I'm a little mad
right now I don't like being defeated by
technology that's one of the things that
makes me a good hacker um so I spent a
lot of time and I over indexed on
finding this pop chain so if anyone can
find a popchain in WordPress core uh or
any plugins above five million installs
then I will be very impressed because I
spent a lot of time and I couldn't do
that uh so there's a little challenge
for you uh WordPress uh enthusiasts in
the audience I'm sure it's only a matter
time before I add a new one yeah well
they need to add one right you know
there there's gadgets I man I I swear
Ram I went down every single path I got
really meticulous about it too man I
started like saying okay here are all my
sources like I started drawing you know
I almost like that Pepe you like
whatever it is the dude that's like you
know there's like strings all the place
I know what you're talking
about yeah exactly and and um and yeah I
was like that except for the pop chains
and Joel is like Justin chill out dude
like this is not you know and this is
not even like you know top dollar Bounty
for me normally either so it's just like
I will admit to searching for all the
destructor uh methods in every plugin I
look at it's nuts man just in case just
in case I don't know I want one give me
one critical thinking listeners please
that would Soothe My Soul um all right
Ram we're coming to the end um we're
going to hit uh WP escalations we're
going to hit WordPress escalations ways
to sort of escalate impact in WordPress
then we're going to swing back around to
your bugs and we'll call it a wrap um
all right so talk to me about some some
WordPress escalations I wrote down some
some basic ones here for example uh one
that you taught me in in a fine little
vulnerability exchange uh file deletion
of WPC result in RC can you talk about
that a little bit Yeah so uh when you
delete thep config file uh the WordPress
site thinks it's being newly set up
which means that the first person to
visit the site gets to uh tell it what
database connection information it needs
to use which means if you already have a
database set up somewhere else you can
just point it at that existing database
that already has you as an administrator
right or you know add a new admin
account and uh log in and then you can
edit plugin files install file manager
plugins uh run code on the server you
own the site uh you might lose access to
the old database uh depends on if you
want anything in there but if there's
any backups you know you got those or
you might not right because a lot of
times people make WP config backup files
exactly and then you can download those
and then you have access to the database
instead of the site or yeah and then
after you you know put your little shell
your little reverse shell on there you
know then you can just sub the old WP
config file back in and then boom Pro
tip WordPress still uses md5 for
password
hashing it uses a lot of rounds oh no
way really that's a lot of rounds of md5
but still md5 wow I'm sure that's gonna
bite him in the butt someday um it does
use salt but you know yeah yeah I I did
notice that um so I guess the next one
on the list here so so that's great if
you got arbitrary file deletion results
in RC WP config boom you're done next
one on the list here stored blind xss to
rce Via admin hijacking and then edit
edting the plugins obviously if you're
an administrator you have the ability to
edit plugin code that's one of the the
features of Wordpress so anybody who's
new to Wordpress should know that um you
or you can add new administrators
there's a fancy little JavaScript going
around I was so happy I'm still taking
some I'm taking the OSP and uh I was so
happy to see this little JavaScript I
was like I know that guy yeah yeah this
it's just this character encoded
JavaScript that adds a new admin user
that's great I love that because it
makes it so easy to implement I think
hack Luke has something out there for
that too he's he's great um and then and
then so tell me about some of the ones
you added here that that are ways to
escalate privileges in WordPress uh so
we sort of discussed this already but uh
if you have update options uh you can
set the default role to administrator
and enable user registration yeah yeah
and we already discussed about how you
can use uh hardcoded options for uh
cross-site scripting okay gotcha so so a
lot a lot of the ones that that are came
to mind surrounding this as well are
options related ones if you have
arbitrary option update then just boom
user registration boom default user uh
should be an admin and then you're
you're in yeah that's good yeah we
actually discussed a lot of these at
least I'm looking at them we did yeah
yeah so this is good the only other one
that's down there is this uh roll your
own password reset functionality yeah um
a lot of plugins uh sort of use less
than secure practices they don't use all
of the built-in password reset
functionality again you'll see this in a
lot of like membership plugins other
plug that are designed to keep track of
users and take their money for Stu and
uh yeah uh a lot of them will have
insecure password reset functionality
like it'll you know set a second uh
it'll it'll set like a reset code that's
deterministic and easily Gass or it'll
let you set the user ID to reset the
password for even if it's not your user
ID you'll send yourself a password reset
and then you click on the link but you
just spoof out your user ID for the
other user and you can reset their
password man there's so there's so many
things like that whenever you try to
bypass traditional functionality that
that gets really tricky when when you
said predicting you know being able to
predict you know what the the reset
token might be excuse me it made me
think of a function where I found a
vulnerability in some PHP code the other
day unique ID uh in PHP is literally
it's uh unu ni IQ ID right it reads
unique ID yeah not a unique idea at all
it's not pseudo it's just it's is it
even pseudo random it's it's just
timestamp based pretty much so oh yeah
yeah that that's another one of the
things that you see with bad password
resets they'll basically just set the
code to the current exact time it's like
oh no this is so bad and so unique ID
one of the plugins I was looking at the
other day was using it as like a temp
directory um name and I was like this is
not good because we can guess that um
and so definitely some bones to be found
there it might even beile to just grap
all the PHP source code for Unique ID of
the plugins and see where it's being
used because I'm sure a bunch of bugs
would fall out of that absolutely yeah
word WordPress is one of the places
where a lot of those vulnerabilities you
think are just theoretical end up being
entirely practical to exploit yeah
that's great and and and I I'll mention
as well just for any of those um
listening I actually mirrored I have a
piece of code that runs every day and
mirrors the um GitHub I mean the s n
plugins that are in uh you know on the
plugins page for for WordPress it
mirrors them into a GitHub uh
organization and that is um github.com
I'm G to type it in as I'm as I'm doing
it uh SL WordPress plug-in directory
that's one that I maintain um and
essentially you can see diffs on any
changes that are being made there um
this is a part of my own personal um
automation uh and so you can see any
changes being made there to various
plugins and new code that's being pushed
and you can diff it with with with uh oh
my
gosh you know as I'm talking about this
I just started scrolling through there
and I see a vulnerability that's
hilarious uh well gonna go ahead and uh
bookmark that bad boy um but yeah go
ahead and and head over to github.com
WordPress plugin directory and then you
can search within that organization on
GitHub and you'll be able to do stuff
like look for Unique ID but I will
probably do that before you uh before
this EP so glad that you've done that
because we used to use WP directory. net
and it has gone down yeah yeah it was it
was a little bit of pain in the ass
especially in the beginning because
there's like a a limit on the number of
repositories you can create in a certain
time frame on GitHub so I had to like
write a script that would be like all
right wait upload wait upload you know
that sort of thing but it's all
automated now it's all in a Chron tab
now so should be uh easy searching for
any of you guys that are interested in
Mass searching uh WordPress uh plugins
um all righty with that I think we
finished the weird or the WordPress uh
escalation section let's get back to the
bugos uh RAM let's talk about the rest
of them I guess let's go ahead and
briefly revisit the um one now that we
know a little bit more about uh the the
Elementor uh remote code execution one
so this was a scenario ah okay add
action admin and it we talked about this
so this is way you hook into uh you you
provide a call back function for
specific Hooks and admin in it one can
be triggered from an unauthenticated
context and then also can be triggered
by visiting literally anything under
wp-admin right correct yeah okay and and
in this scenario I'm I'm gonna try to
I'm gonna do a reverse right up here I'm
gonna summarize it and you can tell me
if I'm right um so uh in this scenario
it says uh wpor doing Ajax which I
assume is just a check to to that to
whether it's uh being an Ajax request or
not and then you got the wp verify nons
which does make it require some sort of
authentication right because the user ID
has to be associated with uh specific
thing for the nons and you have to be
able to access it and but Elementor uses
one nons for a lot of stuff I mean they
got more than one but they use the same
one for most things very cool and then
so using that you can just trigger the
upgrade of the Elementor plugin and
provide PHP code which is run on the
server rip dude that's a bad one that is
a bad one I'm I'm glad you uh pounded
that one out before they that was there
for too many too many versions because
that would have been a bad one yeah and
technically was an admin Ajax one but
they did it a weird way where it didn't
actually register the Ajax hook it just
checked if you happen to be on the Ajax
page oh interesting okay cool huh that
that little function looks a little
interesting there um let's go ahead and
talk about the uh ssrf the next one
subscriber plus ssrf also all of these
writeups that um R is sort of talking
about these are these are public and
they are in in more detail on the word
fence blog which will link uh below um
and I just want to say you
know we we cover a lot of writeups and
stuff like that here on critical
thinking and uh the ones done a lot of
the ones done from like a corporate
perspective are kind
ofme the word the word the word fence
ones are very good and clearly very
technically in-depth so I had quite as
many screenshots for the Elementor one
just because I think I was in a hurry
for that one but yeah yeah no problem
and and they're they're very useful for
Education when you're trying to do uh
learn how to do WordPress plug-in
assessments so I I'm trying to make a
little bit of a corpus here I I've Ving
dreed almost all of them uh so I've seen
these before but uh I'll let you sort of
take take it from from there on this one
okay so uh the credential stealing
server side request for Daran uh this
was in the getwid uh Gutenberg blocks
plug-in which has a bunch of installs
pretty popular yeah not that many but uh
they registered a rest out uh to get
remote content and the permission check
was just current user can read which is
the one capability that subscribers
have but that does mean that it ran a
non check so you couldn't C surf this
but it did mean that you know if you
were a subscriber you could retrieve
arbitrary content from arbitrary URLs
and if you're on an ec2 box then there
you can pass it a specific uh local IP
URL incidentally uh WordPress has a WP
safe remote yet that prevents this from
happening but no one uses it oh really
oh is that like a like a non-default
setting on WP uh retrieve remote or
whatever or remote Deb yeah interesting
so I'm looking at the code here
essentially all they do is you know get
UND or dollar signore getet get the
content URI so get the URL they pass it
directly decod it they just pass it
directly right on yeah Escape it there
and then pass it directly into remote
get which gets the result back did you
un decode it and then they just send it
right back out realistically the biggest
impediment to se surf is the um request
you know expecting it in some format
that isn't what I want so the fact that
this is in Json is like hey that's
perfect yeah Json that's a very very LAX
consideration and and definitely
correlates really well to the AWS uh ec2
API because everything is in Json in
those scenarios exactly which is great
um very cool this is it and and I'm
wondering also wpor remote getet you
can't if you have full direct access to
the URL that's associated with there is
there anything else you can do with PHP
related oh yeah no if it's echoing out
that information uh and you happen to
have access to the remote URL you can
put like a cross-site scripting uh you
can put like a cross-site scripting
payload if it's putting the contents of
that remote URL somewhere then you can
get rce a little more rare but yeah but
what about like um can you give it a URL
that has like a PHP scheme like uh PHP
filters or like a file scheme you know
file colon SL do you know if that works
with WP remote get or does that
something you have to elsewhere I don't
think it works for uh non-standard
pseudo uh protocols but I will have to
check that yeah that' be something
interesting we may we may uh insert
something here if if it does but I
imagine it would just be used for um
remote get I imagine that would just be
used for yeah I mean it says right here
performs HTTP request I think it's
explicitly for HTTP related
functionality otherwise cool I know
otherwise that would be pretty fun
because you could do some you could do
some tricky stuff with PHP related um
schemes that are supported um very cool
ram let's go ahead and hit this last one
here this is unauthentic assess via the
user agent header wow this seems pretty
cool I mean it's it's pretty basic but
you know it was one of the more recent
ones just because I haven't been
focusing as much on vulnerability
research in the past year or so so
uh but yeah it's it was in a security
plugin uh and uh that that always that
always feels good and you know how
security plugins will you know show you
which requests were blocked or which IPS
were blocked and they'll show you the
user agent they forgot to escape that on
output that's clutch that's actually a
really interesting and that's the thing
we keep on seeing this in security
plugins I want to see even word word
fence has something like this at some
point way back in like version or
something yeah yeah where you're where
you're because there's so much data to
log because it's a security related
thing something is going to pop in there
that's a little bit tricky exactly very
interesting so then they were just e
echoing out the refer directly I guess
maybe after URL decoding it or something
like that and then that was actually
just being embedded right into the Dom
so you could just redirect it from a
page that had that in the URL and
actually that that makes sense as well
I'll add a little caveat here
um and I don't know if you I wasn't even
reflected it was stored so you could
just visit the site do something that
get that would get you blocked with the
user agent with the malicious user agent
in there and uh of course because it's
it's a logging plugin exactly that that
makes so much sense okay I was say refer
it was user agent I think it's just
because I saw a referral one recently
too oh you're good and and it actually
that makes sense with the user agent and
and how it would be stored there and and
output it that's something people would
want to see it makes me think of a
different thing with the refer since we
kind of had that little mix up um Chrome
recently I guess I don't know when it
was maybe 2019 or something so maybe not
that recently um started not providing a
refer in the and for cross-site refers
Beyond just the the domain so so now if
you're going from from p. reator.com or
whatever to a different site the only
thing you'll see in the refer is you
know htps domain.com you won't see the
path um but when you're using it for
exploits that's something that's
controlled on the first page side so you
define a referral policy using the metat
tag that says please send my referer and
then you can send you know a a referer a
full referrer to the victim side right
and then you know if they're URL
decoding it or Bas 64 decoding it or
whatever and then doing something with
it then you can still get syncs so we we
actually just uh we were I remember just
discussing something like that with
Chloe I want to say earlier this week
this was like I bet you could do that
and uh yeah yeah I've used it a couple
times in X plates it's pretty fun
because there's like this default secure
default that they put into place but
then you know because it's from your
side you can just turn it off and the
the the whole point is and it was very
needed because we were using you know
image image tag injection and stuff like
that to link leak oath uh codes or
something like that that were in the URL
that would be sent along with the refer
so very smart move by Chrome um but in
this specific scenario you can sort of
undo the work and and use their for
policy get away with even more exactly
yeah so very cool stuff there um dude
great bugs rce and the top plugin at a
beautiful ssrf to uh ec2 metadata and a
great uh accs on a security plugin love
to see that um Ram this has been this
has been great dude and uh I I I really
appreciate you coming on obviously word
fence uh has is you know working at word
fence you've really developed a lot of
great skills there um anything you want
to shout out uh before you before we hop
off uh just that uh check out our bug
Bounty program uh I think there we we're
probably gonna have some very exciting
news in the very near future so keep an
a out and uh I look forward to
processing all your bugs yeah yeah I'm
sure you'll be getting a lot more from
the uh stuff guys yeah girls and
everyone else I can speak I can speak
from experience that Ram really enjoys
getting cool bugs cuz we've kind of
geeked out together over Discord over a
couple things um so very cool stuff well
thanks for coming on man and I think
that's the
[Music]
pod